

Summary

# Vardan Sedha

vardan9694@gmail.com +44 7469 641 969

London - Eligible to work in the UK & open to relocation.

Versatile and result driven. 3+ years of experience in engineering and consultancy roles. Deep interest in machines with insightful solution-oriented approach and capable of various productivity improvement techniques. Eventual career goal is to become a fully-qualified and experienced Mechanical Engineer, with a long-term aspiration of becoming an Engineering Project Manager.

# Experience

#### Formel D, UK

New Holland Agriculture, Basildon

Work

June 2021 -Present

#### **Vehicle Mechanic**

- Repaired a fleet of 150+ tractors.
- Completing assembly, replacement and repair of different Tractor models.
- Accustomed to a full working system of plant and UK systems.
- Used tools in a fast paced automotive sector assembly line.
- Learned the inner functioning and mechanisms of tractors.

# India

## June 2018 -March 2021

Client Projects: Xylem Water Solutions Godrej Aerospace Faiveley Transport

## Change Et. Al. Lead Process Improvement Consultant

- Decreased lead time by 51.4%, thus increased production output by 106% with no added resources in Faiveley Transport.
- Researching, analysing and building a large amount of minuscule data points to improve the current system.
- Optimising performance via MOST, Time Study, OEE, Capacity Calculations, Assembly Line Balancing, VSM, 5S, Kaizen Culture, Lean Manufacturing Principle & Methodologies.
- Kick off Kaizen brainstorming with top management regarding plant layout. assembly sequencing, storage optimization and reducing individual operation timings.
- Designing innovative processes specific to assembly / testing electromechanical valves and manifolds.
- Creating and managing project plans & providing guidance from warehouse to management levels.
- Introducing new techniques for shop floor automation.
- Presenting and executing a fully optimized workflow in each project.
- Coaching the client for the upgraded practices via MOST (Maynard Operation Sequence Technique).

# Modern Manufacturers Pvt. Ltd.

January - April 2018

## **Trainee Production Engineer**

- Supervising technical moulding processes with efficient utilisation of resources.
- Devising solutions for process improvement via root cause analysis.
- Training operators & devising company-wide SOP with updated processes.
- Reactive maintenance of Injection Moulding Equipment.

## Biostadt India Pvt. Ltd.

July -December 2017

# **Trainee Maintenance Mechanical Engineer**

- Active maintenance of mixing and packaging machineries, pumps, motors, chillers, HVAC, AC units, generators with senior Engineer.
- Extensive use of hand tools for analysing and devising technical solutions for sudden breakdowns.

# Education

August 2012 – May 2017

# Bachelor & Master of Technology in Manufacturing, Mechanical Engineering

Gautam Buddha University, India

CGPA: 7.91

#### **Publications**

**Analysis of Warpage in Injection Moulded Parts via Taguchi Method** (International Journal of Production Engineering)

Certifications NEBOSH International General Certificate in Occupational Health and Safet June 2021	ty
Skills  Design - AutoCAD, comprehending Engineering Drawings  Management - Microsoft Office, ERP (SAP, Oracle)  Fabrication - CNC, Lathe, Grinding, TIG, MIG, Spot Welding	
, and a second containing, and, and, appears and	